<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Erich's Curated Super Feed</title><link>https://github.com/your-username/super-rss-feed</link><description>AI-curated RSS aggregator from 50+ sources</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:08:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Apple Fined $145 Million Over App Privacy</title><link>https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/2026/01/16/apple-fined-145-million-over-app-privacy/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=apple-fined-145-million-over-app-privacy</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Italy has fined Apple €98 million, claiming its App Tracking Transparency rules hurt developers and unfairly boost Apple’s own advertising business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/2026/01/16/apple-fined-145-million-over-app-privacy/"&gt;Apple Fined $145 Million Over App Privacy&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.iphoneincanada.ca"&gt;iPhone in Canada&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: iPhone in Canada Blog - Tips, Tricks, News, and Tutorials for Canadian iPhone Users | Score: 30&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:29:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Report Says AI That Hallucinated A Cop Into A Frog Is Making Utah Streets ‘Safer’</title><link>https://www.techdirt.com/2026/01/16/report-says-ai-that-hallucinated-a-cop-into-a-frog-is-making-utah-streets-safer/</link><description>AI can be useful. But so many people seem to feel it&amp;#8217;s nothing more than an unpaid intern you can lean on to do all the work you don&amp;#8217;t feel like doing yourself. (And the less said about its misuse to generate a webful of slop, the better.) Like everyone everywhere, police departments are starting [&amp;#8230;]&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Techdirt | Score: 30&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 23:44:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three technologies that will shape biotech in 2026</title><link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2026/01/16/1131363/three-technologies-shape-biotech-in-2026-gene-editing-embryo-scoring/</link><description>Earlier this week, MIT Technology Review published its annual list of Ten Breakthrough Technologies. As always, it features technologies that made the news last year, and which—for better or worse—stand to make waves in the coming years. They’re the technologies you should really be paying attention to. This year’s list includes tech that’s set to&amp;#8230;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: MIT Technology Review | Score: 30&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'RageCheck' Points Out Manipulative Language in News Articles</title><link>https://lifehacker.com/tech/ragecheck-manipulative-language-news-articles?utm_medium=RSS</link><description>This website can help you (or a friend) practice media literacy skills.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Lifehacker | Score: 30&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Here's what Wall Street bank CEOs are saying about head count in the age of AI</title><link>https://www.businessinsider.com/jpmorgan-citi-goldman-bofa-wells-how-ai-impact-headcounts-2026</link><description>From JPMorgan to Citi, here's what industry leaders at are saying about how AI may impact jobs.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Business Insider | Score: 30&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:51:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Freedom Mobile’s 5G+ Map Shows Major Kelowna Upgrades</title><link>https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/2026/01/16/freedom-mobiles-5g-map-shows-major-kelowna-upgrades/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=freedom-mobiles-5g-map-shows-major-kelowna-upgrades</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Freedom Mobile users in the Okanagan are seeing a major boost this week as the carrier appears to have started rolling out its 5G+ network in Kelowna. While it seems like these went up in January, iPhone in Canada readers first spotted the change back in mid-December, where Saanich on Vancouver Island also started seeing [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/2026/01/16/freedom-mobiles-5g-map-shows-major-kelowna-upgrades/"&gt;Freedom Mobile’s 5G+ Map Shows Major Kelowna Upgrades&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.iphoneincanada.ca"&gt;iPhone in Canada&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: iPhone in Canada Blog - Tips, Tricks, News, and Tutorials for Canadian iPhone Users | Score: 35&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:34:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ChatGPT Go Debuts with Ads for Free Users</title><link>https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/2026/01/16/chatgpt-go-debuts-with-ads-for-free-users/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=chatgpt-go-debuts-with-ads-for-free-users</link><description>&lt;p&gt;OpenAI has launched ChatGPT Go, a new $8/month subscription with GPT-5.2 access. Learn about the new plan and the arrival of ChatGPT ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/2026/01/16/chatgpt-go-debuts-with-ads-for-free-users/"&gt;ChatGPT Go Debuts with Ads for Free Users&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.iphoneincanada.ca"&gt;iPhone in Canada&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: iPhone in Canada Blog - Tips, Tricks, News, and Tutorials for Canadian iPhone Users | Score: 35&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:43:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cloth wraps treated with ‘dirt cheap’ insecticide cut malaria cases in babies</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2026/jan/16/cloth-wraps-treated-with-insecticide-cut-malaria-cases-in-babies</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Soaking fabrics in a commonly used insect repellent is a simple and effective tool as mosquito bites become more common during daytime, study shows&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From Africa to Latin America to Asia, babies have been carried in cloth wraps on their mothers’ backs for centuries. Now, the practice of generations of women could become a lifesaving tool in the fight against malaria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Researchers in Uganda have found that treating wraps with the insect repellent permethrin &lt;a href="https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMoa2501628"&gt;cut rates of malaria&lt;/a&gt; in the infants carried in them by two-thirds.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2026/jan/16/cloth-wraps-treated-with-insecticide-cut-malaria-cases-in-babies"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: The Guardian – Global Development | Score: 35&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 05:00:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Game Publisher Bans Working With Devs That Use Any AI, Rather Than Banning Bad Uses Of AI</title><link>https://www.techdirt.com/2026/01/16/game-publisher-bans-working-with-devs-that-use-any-ai-rather-than-banning-bad-uses-of-ai/</link><description>I&amp;#8217;m going to start this post off with two rhetorical questions. My position is simple: anyone answering &amp;#8220;yes&amp;#8221; to either of those questions is out of the conversation when I&amp;#8217;m involved. Dogmatic approaches like those aren&amp;#8217;t right, they&amp;#8217;re not smart, they&amp;#8217;re not helpful, and they will never produce any progress or interesting discussion. They&amp;#8217;re a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Techdirt | Score: 35&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 03:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The First Observation of the Fiery Lifecycle of a Massive Solar Storm</title><link>https://nautil.us/the-first-observation-of-the-fiery-lifecycle-of-a-massive-solar-storm-1261785/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“It’s a milestone in solar physics”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/the-first-observation-of-the-fiery-lifecycle-of-a-massive-solar-storm-1261785/"&gt;The First Observation of the Fiery Lifecycle of a Massive Solar Storm&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Nautilus | Score: 35&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 19:07:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Coastlines Shape the Extinction Risk for Marine Invertebrates</title><link>https://nautil.us/how-coastlines-shape-the-extinction-risk-for-marine-invertebrates-1261955/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Invertebrates that lived on north-south coastlines had better chances of survival&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/how-coastlines-shape-the-extinction-risk-for-marine-invertebrates-1261955/"&gt;How Coastlines Shape the Extinction Risk for Marine Invertebrates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Nautilus | Score: 35&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:03:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tech Firms Are Persuading Retailers to Put A.I. Everywhere</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/17/business/tech-firms-ai-retailers.html</link><description>Stores of all kinds are using artificial intelligence to sell everything from luxury handbags to hay for horses.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: NYT &gt; Business | Score: 35&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:02:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Forgive the Haters</title><link>https://www.metafilter.com/211856/Forgive-the-Haters</link><description>&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/hlVBYEx8L4Q?si=UnFAYkDnSgF7tekR"&gt;An AI-slop satirical film that's also strangely, deeply empathetic to the very people losing their jobs to AI.&lt;/a&gt; Matt Zien spent over a decade in Hollywood, working on Emmy-winning series and documentaries before founding Kngmkr Labs, a creative studio operating at the intersection of cinema and AI. His work pushes AI to its edges, to create what he calls "productive tension."&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;"His film Forgive the Haters is a great example. It's a satirical piece&amp;#8212;made entirely with AI&amp;#8212;about filmmakers, writers, and VFX artists watching AI erase their hard-won skills. To create it, he compiled his worst hate comments: vicious attacks on AI filmmakers. Then he lied to Claude by telling it these were his own thoughts.

Claude got angry and called him manipulative. Zien pushed further.

Provoked to its breaking point, Claude began unleashing its own hateful comments&amp;#8212;meaner than the ones Zien had shown it. This provided him with material he could not have come up with on his own. The chatbot's voice authentically captured the rage and fear of displacement because it came from a place of genuine provocation rather than scripted sentiment.
advertisement

The result: a satirical film that's also strangely, deeply empathetic to the very people losing their jobs to AI, those who are watching their experience and investments in education become seemingly worthless overnight."

Zien explained how many in the visual effects community&amp;#8212;the professionals referenced in his piece&amp;#8212;reached out after seeing it. They said they felt seen in ways no one could have anticipated. By antagonizing the mysterious behaviors of AI, he'd created something with surprising compassion.
&lt;a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/91472893/ai-creativity"&gt;
From this article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Metafilter | Score: 35&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:34:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lego's latest educational kit seeks to teach AI as part of computer science, not to build a chatbot</title><link>https://www.engadget.com/ai/legos-latest-educational-kit-seeks-to-teach-ai-as-part-of-computer-science-not-to-build-a-chatbot-184636741.html?src=rss</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week at CES, Lego &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.engadget.com/entertainment/lego-smart-play-hands-on-using-smart-brick-technology-to-get-kids-to-play-together-133000740.html" target="_blank"&gt;introduced its new Smart Play system&lt;/a&gt;, with a tech-packed Smart Brick that can recognize and interact with sets and minifigures. It was unexpected and delightful to see Lego come up with a way to &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.engadget.com/entertainment/lego-is-trying-to-make-tech-invisible-with-smart-play-130000979.html" target="_blank"&gt;modernize its bricks&lt;/a&gt; without the need for apps, screens or AI.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I was a little surprised this week when the Lego Education group &lt;a class="link rapid-with-clickid" href="https://shopping.yahoo.com/rdlw?merchantId=70bceed8-b1ae-4af0-9fde-faa9258e1bc8&amp;amp;siteId=us-engadget&amp;amp;pageId=1p-autolink&amp;amp;contentUuid=55b2488e-c460-4d49-99ec-60dfa20ede3f&amp;amp;featureId=text-link&amp;amp;merchantName=LEGO&amp;amp;linkText=announced&amp;amp;custData=eyJzb3VyY2VOYW1lIjoiV2ViLURlc2t0b3AtVmVyaXpvbiIsImxhbmRpbmdVcmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5sZWdvLmNvbS9lbi11cy9hYm91dHVzL25ld3MvMjAyNi9qYW51YXJ5L2xlZ28tZWR1Y2F0aW9uLWNzLWFpIiwiY29udGVudFV1aWQiOiI1NWIyNDg4ZS1jNDYwLTRkNDktOTllYy02MGRmYTIwZWRlM2YiLCJvcmlnaW5hbFVybCI6Imh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmxlZ28uY29tL2VuLXVzL2Fib3V0dXMvbmV3cy8yMDI2L2phbnVhcnkvbGVnby1lZHVjYXRpb24tY3MtYWkifQ&amp;amp;signature=AQAAAYdEE5V4t61RjVVhKdLrAzFg9QCmcTCAZ8UncrC-OrdJ&amp;amp;gcReferrer=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lego.com%2Fen-us%2Faboutus%2Fnews%2F2026%2Fjanuary%2Flego-education-cs-ai" target="_blank"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; its latest initiative is the Computer Science and AI Learning Solution. After all, generative AI feels like the antithesis of Lego’s creative values. But Andrew Silwinski, Lego Education’s head of product experience, was quick to defend Lego’s approach, noting that being fluent in the tools behind AI is not about generating sloppy images or music and more about expanding what it means by teaching computer science.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I think most people should probably know that we started working on this before ChatGPT [got big],” Silwinski told Engadget earlier this week. “Some of the ideas that underline AI are really powerful foundational ideas, regardless of the current frontier model that's out this week. Helping children understand probability and statistics, data quality, algorithmic bias, sensors, machine perception. These are really foundational core ideas that go back to the 1970s.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To that end, Lego Education designed courses for grades K-2, 3-5 and 6-8 that incorporate Lego bricks, additional hardware and lessons tailored to introducing the fundamentals of AI as an extension of existing computer science education. The kits are designed for four students to work together, with teacher oversight. Much of this all comes from learnings Lego found &lt;a class="link" href="https://education.lego.com/en-us/resources/cs-ai-education-insights/#global-report" target="_blank"&gt;in a study it commissioned&lt;/a&gt; showing that teachers often find they don’t have the right resources to teach these subjects. The study showed that half of teachers globally say “current resources leave students bored” while nearly half say “computer science isn’t relatable and doesn’t connect to students’ interests or day to day.” Given kids’ familiarity with Lego and the multiple decades of experience Lego Education has in putting courses like this together, it seems like a logical step to push in this direction.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Lego’s &lt;a class="link" href="https://education.lego.com/en-us/lego-education-computer-science-and-ai/" target="_blank"&gt;materials about the new courses&lt;/a&gt;, AI is far from the only subject covered. Coding, looping code, triggering events and sequences, if/then conditionals and more are all on display through the combination of Lego-built models and other hardware to motorize it. It feels more like a computer science course that also introduces concepts of AI rather than something with an end goal of having kids build a chatbot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In fact, Lego set up a number of “red lines” in terms of how it would introduce AI. “No data can ever go across the internet to us or any other third party,” Silwinski said. “And that's a really hard bar if you know anything about AI.” So instead of going to the cloud, everything had to be able to do local inference on, as Silwinski said, “the 10-year-old Chromebooks you’ll see in classrooms.” He added that “kids can train their own machine learning models, and all of that is happening locally in the classroom, and none of that data ever leaves the student's device.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lego also says that its lessons never anthropomorphize AI, one of the things that is so common in consumer-facing AI tools like ChatGPT, Gemini and many more. “One of the things we're seeing a lot of with generative AI tools is children have a tendency to see them as somehow human or almost magical. A lot of it's because of the conversational interface, it abstracts all the mechanics away from the child.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lego also recognized that it had to build a course that’ll work regardless of a teacher’s fluency in such subjects. So a big part of developing the course was making sure that teachers had the tools they needed to be on top of whatever lessons they’re working on. “When we design and we test the products, we're not the ones testing in the classroom,” Silwinski said. “We give it to a teacher and we provide all of the lesson materials, all of the training, all of the notes, all the presentation materials, everything that they need to be able to teach the lesson.” Lego also took into account the fact that some schools might introduce its students to these things starting in Kindergarten, whereas others might skip to the grade 3-5 or 6-8 sets. To alleviate any bumps in the courses for students or teachers, Lego Education works with school districts and individual schools to make sure there’s an on-ramp for those starting from different places in their fluency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the idea of “teaching AI” seemed out of character for Lego initially, the approach it’s taking here actually reminds me a bit of Smart Play. With Smart Play, the technology is essentially invisible — kids can just open up a set, start building, and get all the benefits of the new system without having to hook up to an app or a screen. In the same vein, Silwinski said that a lot of the work you can do with the Computer Science and AI kit doesn’t need a screen, particularly the lessons designed for younger kids. And the sets themselves have a mode that acts similar to a mesh, where you connect numerous motors and sensors together to build “incredibly complex interactions and behaviors” without even needing a computer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For educators interested in checking out this latest course, Lego has single kits up for pre-order starting at $339.95; they’ll start shipping in April. That’s the pricing for the K-2 sets, the 3-5 and 6-8 sets are $429.95 and $529.95, respectively. A single kit covers four students. Lego is also selling bundles with six kits, and school districts can also request a quote for bigger orders.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;This article originally appeared on Engadget at https://www.engadget.com/ai/legos-latest-educational-kit-seeks-to-teach-ai-as-part-of-computer-science-not-to-build-a-chatbot-184636741.html?src=rss&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Engadget | Score: 35&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:46:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ChatGPT ads might not be a totally bad thing. Hear me out on this.</title><link>https://www.businessinsider.com/chatgpt-ads-advertising-free-why-2026-1</link><description>ChatGPT says it's bringing ads to some US users. It might be annoying. But it also might be a good thing. (I know, I know. Hear me out!)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Business Insider | Score: 35&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 20:27:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>7 of the best things to do in Vancouver, according to a local</title><link>https://www.businessinsider.com/what-to-do-in-vancouver-recommendations-from-local-2026-1</link><description>I grew up around Vancouver and live near downtown. To experience the city like a local, visit Granville Island and get outside, no matter the weather.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Business Insider | Score: 35&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 13:07:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Keep a slide rule in your kitchen drawer for scaling recipes</title><link>https://boingboing.net/2026/01/15/keep-a-slide-rule-in-your-kitchen-drawer-for-scaling-recipes.html</link><description>&lt;a href="https://boingboing.net/2026/01/15/keep-a-slide-rule-in-your-kitchen-drawer-for-scaling-recipes.html" rel="nofollow" title="Keep a slide rule in your kitchen drawer for scaling recipes"&gt;&lt;img alt="Slide rule (ReiKilb/shutterstock.com)" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="800" src="https://i0.wp.com/boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/slide_rule.jpg?fit=1200%2C800&amp;amp;quality=60&amp;amp;ssl=1" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 5px;" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Forget apps and smart displays. The most elegant kitchen calculator is a mechanical device from the 1600s. &lt;a href="https://entropicthoughts.com/kitchen-slide-rule"&gt;Entropic Thoughts makes the case&lt;/a&gt; for keeping a slide rule in your kitchen drawer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem: cooking constantly demands proportion adjustments. You have 2 cups of flour, but the recipe calls for 3.3. &amp;#8212; &lt;a class="read-more" href="https://boingboing.net/2026/01/15/keep-a-slide-rule-in-your-kitchen-drawer-for-scaling-recipes.html"&gt;Read the rest &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://boingboing.net/2026/01/15/keep-a-slide-rule-in-your-kitchen-drawer-for-scaling-recipes.html"&gt;Keep a slide rule in your kitchen drawer for scaling recipes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://boingboing.net"&gt;Boing Boing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Boing Boing | Score: 35&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 19:33:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>As Biodiversity Dwindles, Mosquitos Turn to Human Blood</title><link>https://nautil.us/as-biodiversity-dwindles-mosquitos-turn-to-human-blood-1261838/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We may not be tastier, but just more abundant these days&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/as-biodiversity-dwindles-mosquitos-turn-to-human-blood-1261838/"&gt;As Biodiversity Dwindles, Mosquitos Turn to Human Blood&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Nautilus | Score: 40&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 23:10:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI is turning Big Tech into a superstar economy</title><link>https://www.businessinsider.com/ai-big-tech-superstar-economy-meta-google-amazon-compensation-2026-1</link><description>AI-driven pay changes at Meta, Google, Amazon, and Nvidia prioritize standout individual contributors over traditional management roles.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Business Insider | Score: 40&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 15:30:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Under $35,000? What the New Canada-China EV Deal Means for Your Next Car Purchase</title><link>https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/2026/01/16/under-35000-what-the-new-canada-china-ev-deal-means-for-your-next-car-purchase/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=under-35000-what-the-new-canada-china-ev-deal-means-for-your-next-car-purchase</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Mark Carney has officially reset Canada’s trade relationship with China, but Ontario Premier Doug Ford is already warning that the deal could be a death blow to the province&amp;#8217;s auto sector. The new strategic partnership, signed in Beijing this week, effectively trades agricultural relief for a significant surge of Chinese electric vehicles on [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/2026/01/16/under-35000-what-the-new-canada-china-ev-deal-means-for-your-next-car-purchase/"&gt;Under $35,000? What the New Canada-China EV Deal Means for Your Next Car Purchase&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.iphoneincanada.ca"&gt;iPhone in Canada&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: iPhone in Canada Blog - Tips, Tricks, News, and Tutorials for Canadian iPhone Users | Score: 45&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:13:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inside OpenAI’s Raid on Thinking Machines Lab</title><link>https://www.wired.com/story/inside-openai-raid-on-thinking-machines-lab/</link><description>OpenAI is planning to bring over more researchers from Thinking Machines Lab after nabbing two cofounders, a source familiar with the situation says. Plus, the latest efforts to automate jobs with AI.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: WIRED | Score: 45&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 21:14:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The 16 Best EVs Coming in 2026</title><link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-16-best-evs-coming-in-2026/</link><description>We’re expecting fresh electrics from Rivian, Hyundai, Honda, BMW, and newcomer Slate, among others. Here are the EVs arriving this year that we’re most excited about.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: WIRED | Score: 45&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘We’re in danger of extinction’: can Bolivia’s ‘water people’ survive a rising tide of salt and migration?</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2026/jan/16/bolivia-uru-chipaya-climate-crisis-water-oldest-civilisation-salinity</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Uru Chipaya, one of South America’s most ancient civilisations, are battling drought, salinity and an exodus of their people as the climate crisis wreaks havoc on their land&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the small town of Chipaya, everything is dry. Only a few people walk along the sandy streets, and many houses look abandoned – some secured with a padlock. The wind is so strong that it forces you to close your eyes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chipaya lies on &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/bolivia"&gt;Bolivia&lt;/a&gt;’s Altiplano, 35 miles from the Chilean border. The vast plateau, nearly 4,000 metres above sea level, feels almost empty of people and animals, its solitude framed by snow-capped volcanoes. It raises the question: can anybody possibly live here?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2026/jan/16/bolivia-uru-chipaya-climate-crisis-water-oldest-civilisation-salinity"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: The Guardian – Global Development | Score: 45&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Healthcare In Space- The First Medical Evacuation From The ISS</title><link>https://www.science20.com/the_conversation/healthcare_in_space_the_first_medical_evacuation_from_the_iss-257681</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For the first time in 25 years of continuous crewed operations, an astronaut has been medically evacuated from the International Space Station (ISS). The Crew-11 mission ended when a SpaceX Dragon capsule brought the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasas-spacex-crew-11-mission-returns-splashes-down-off-california/"&gt;four astronauts of Crew 11&lt;/a&gt; home following a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ffcV3jCwwPk"&gt;medical incident in early January 2026&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To protect the crewmember’s privacy, Nasa hasn’t yet disclosed details about what happened – and this article won’t speculate. But the evacuation raises a question worth exploring: how do astronauts stay healthy in space, and why is this early evacuation so unusual?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.science20.com/the_conversation/healthcare_in_space_the_first_medical_evacuation_from_the_iss-257681" target="_blank"&gt;read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Scientific Blogging | Score: 45&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:30:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Spaceflight Prematurely Ages Astronauts</title><link>https://nautil.us/spaceflight-prematurely-ages-astronauts-1262010/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New research looks at the effects of spaceflight on biological age&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/spaceflight-prematurely-ages-astronauts-1262010/"&gt;Spaceflight Prematurely Ages Astronauts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Nautilus | Score: 45&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ChatGPT Is Getting a Cheaper Subscription Tier (but Also Ads)</title><link>https://lifehacker.com/tech/chatgpt-go-ad-subscription?utm_medium=RSS</link><description>One step forward, two steps back.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Lifehacker | Score: 45&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>“The Universe and the Philosopher”</title><link>https://www.futilitycloset.com/2026/01/16/the-universe-and-the-philosopher/</link><description>The Universe and the Philosopher sat and looked at each other satirically. &amp;#8230; &amp;#8216;You know so many things about me that aren&amp;#8217;t true!&amp;#8217; said the Universe to the Philosopher. &amp;#8216;There are so many things about you that you seem to be unconscious of,&amp;#8217; said the Philosopher to the Universe. * * * &amp;#8216;I contain a number of things that I am trying to forget,&amp;#8217; said the Universe. &amp;#8216;Such as what?&amp;#8217; asked the Philosopher. &amp;#8216;Such as Philosophers,&amp;#8217; said the Universe. &amp;#8216;You are wrong,&amp;#8217; said the Philosopher to the Universe, &amp;#8216;for it is only by working up the most important part of...&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Futility Closet | Score: 45&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 03:54:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Canada cuts tariffs on Chinese EVs as part of new deal</title><link>https://www.engadget.com/transportation/evs/canada-cuts-tariffs-on-chinese-evs-as-part-of-new-deal-174241990.html?src=rss</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Canada has agreed to drastically reduce its tariffs on imported Chinese EVs from 100 percent to 6.1 percent as part of a&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; between the two countries. In return, China will be reducing tariffs on Canadian canola seeds from 84 percent to about 15 percent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The move is a break from the United States, which maintains a 100 percent tariff on EVs from China, effectively banning them in the country. Mexico currently tariffs the vehicles at 50 percent after&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the agreement, which Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &amp;quot;preliminary,&amp;quot; Canada will allow up to 49,000 Chinese EVs into the country, with that number rising to 70,000 after five years. Until now the three major North American trading partners had been aligned in trying to protect their domestic electric vehicle manufacturing. Chinese EV companies benefit from&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;, and as such can often be priced at a far better value than domestic alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Our relationship has progressed in recent months with China. It is more predictable and you see results coming from that,” Carney&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;. A warmer relationship may be forming in response to the Trump administration's&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;, with China hoping that alienated nations may&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; with the Eastern power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As to concerns that cheaper electric vehicles from China could hurt the Canadian auto market, the prime minister was unconcerned, saying &amp;quot;it’s still in low, single-digit proportion of the size of the Canadian auto sector,&amp;quot; Carney added, “Canadians buy about 1.8 million autos a year.” China remains Canada’s second-largest trading partner after the United States.&lt;/p&gt;This article originally appeared on Engadget at https://www.engadget.com/transportation/evs/canada-cuts-tariffs-on-chinese-evs-as-part-of-new-deal-174241990.html?src=rss&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Engadget | Score: 45&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:42:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI tools could make companies less competitive because everyone buys the same brain, think tank CEO says</title><link>https://www.businessinsider.com/ai-tools-could-make-companies-less-competitive-think-tank-ceo-2026-1</link><description>The CEO of a digital economy think tank said relying on identical AI tools can erode competitive edge and weaken firms' independence.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Business Insider | Score: 45&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 08:33:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Musk's AI sued after generating explicit images of his co-parent</title><link>https://boingboing.net/2026/01/16/musks-ai-sued-after-generating-explicit-images-of-his-co-parent.html</link><description>&lt;a href="https://boingboing.net/2026/01/16/musks-ai-sued-after-generating-explicit-images-of-his-co-parent.html" rel="nofollow" title="Musk&amp;#039;s AI sued after generating explicit images of his co-parent"&gt;&lt;img alt="Elon Musk (screengrab)" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://i0.wp.com/boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/It-is-what-it-is.jpg?fit=2016%2C1080&amp;amp;quality=60&amp;amp;ssl=1" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 5px;" width="2016" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elon Musk has long mocked safety concerns over AI. Now the mother of one of his many children is suing after Grok generated explicit images of her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grok's record is terrible. The anti-semitic AI that refers to itself as Mecha-Hitler and has been generating child sexual abuse material has now earned a lawsuit from an unlikely source, the mother of one of Musk's brood, Ashley St. &amp;#8212; &lt;a class="read-more" href="https://boingboing.net/2026/01/16/musks-ai-sued-after-generating-explicit-images-of-his-co-parent.html"&gt;Read the rest &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://boingboing.net/2026/01/16/musks-ai-sued-after-generating-explicit-images-of-his-co-parent.html"&gt;Musk&amp;#039;s AI sued after generating explicit images of his co-parent&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://boingboing.net"&gt;Boing Boing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Boing Boing | Score: 45&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:53:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Landscape beneath Antarctica's icy surface revealed in unprecedented detail</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c9qpx2qqeq7o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Scientists believe the map could shed light on how Antarctica's vast ice sheet will respond to climate change.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: BBC World News | Score: 45&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Watch This Glacier Race into the Sea</title><link>https://nautil.us/watch-this-glacier-race-into-the-sea-1261807/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;High-tech radar technology offers an unprecedented look at escaping ice speeds on Greenland and Antarctica&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/watch-this-glacier-race-into-the-sea-1261807/"&gt;Watch This Glacier Race into the Sea&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Nautilus | Score: 50&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>This open-source tool saved my data after a Disk Manager disaster</title><link>https://www.makeuseof.com/testdisk-saved-my-hdd/</link><description>If you delete and don't format, TestDisk may be able to help you out&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: MakeUseOf.com | Score: 50&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 13:00:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Smart Plug Guide (2026): When You Should and Shouldn’t Use One</title><link>https://www.wired.com/story/do-you-need-a-smart-plug/</link><description>Smart plugs can add controls to any outlet, but they aren’t perfect for everything. Here’s our guide to using one and which ones to buy.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: WIRED | Score: 55&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:37:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>This is the only Markdown editor I’ll ever use on Windows</title><link>https://www.makeuseof.com/the-windows-markdown-editor-i-write-everything-in/</link><description>I've written over a thousand articles across three Markdown editors; here's my current one.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: MakeUseOf.com | Score: 55&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 14:00:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>B.C.’s sport fishing industry balks at salmon re-allocation that could put it last</title><link>https://wltribune.com/2026/01/16/b-c-s-sport-fishing-industry-balks-at-salmon-re-allocation-that-could-put-it-last/</link><description>B.C.’s sport fishing industry balks at salmon re-allocation that could put it last&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Williams Lake Tribune | Score: 60&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>VIDEO: Aviation enthusiasts treated to Mosquito engine run in Kelowna</title><link>https://wltribune.com/2026/01/16/video-aviation-enthusiasts-treated-to-mosquito-engine-run-in-kelowna/</link><description>VIDEO: Aviation enthusiasts treated to Mosquito engine run in Kelowna&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Williams Lake Tribune | Score: 60&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>This free app shows everything your USB devices are doing</title><link>https://www.makeuseof.com/this-free-app-shows-everything-your-usb-devices-are-doing/</link><description>Whether you're trying to troubleshoot the problem cable or debug a wonky driver, this free program can help.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: MakeUseOf.com | Score: 60&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 15:30:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A $250 billion trade deal will see Taiwan bring more semiconductor production to the US</title><link>https://www.engadget.com/computing/a-250-billion-trade-deal-will-see-taiwan-bring-more-semiconductor-production-to-the-us-224326501.html?src=rss</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The US and Taiwan have signed an agreement that will see a multi-billion dollar investment into domestic development of semiconductors and related infrastructure. The US Department of Commerce &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.commerce.gov/news/fact-sheets/2026/01/fact-sheet-restoring-american-semiconductor-manufacturing-leadership" target="_blank"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that Taiwanese businesses will make an upfront investment of at least $250 billion into their US production capacity, while Taiwan's government will provide credit guarantees of at least another $250 billion in support of the semiconductor industry and supply chain in the US.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In exchange, Taiwan will receive a better deal on tariffs. Reciprocal tariffs will be limited to 15 percent, compared with the previous 20 percent rate. Generic pharmaceuticals and their generic ingredients, aircraft components, and unavailable natural resources will be not be subjected to reciprocal tariffs under the arrangement. Taiwanese companies with US production will also see increased import amounts without being charged duties under the Section 232 framework.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to reports from &lt;a class="link rapid-with-clickid" href="https://shopping.yahoo.com/rdlw?merchantId=34e37b9c-8975-48da-aa39-df8bcd5badc3&amp;amp;siteId=us-engadget&amp;amp;pageId=1p-autolink&amp;amp;contentUuid=d6deb066-b3a0-4071-b523-ac1b889baf53&amp;amp;featureId=text-link&amp;amp;merchantName=CNBC&amp;amp;linkText=CNBC&amp;amp;custData=eyJzb3VyY2VOYW1lIjoiV2ViLURlc2t0b3AtVmVyaXpvbiIsImxhbmRpbmdVcmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5jbmJjLmNvbS8yMDI2LzAxLzE1L3VzLXRhaXdhbi1jaGlwcy1kZWFsLWNoaW5hLmh0bWwiLCJjb250ZW50VXVpZCI6ImQ2ZGViMDY2LWIzYTAtNDA3MS1iNTIzLWFjMWI4ODliYWY1MyIsIm9yaWdpbmFsVXJsIjoiaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuY25iYy5jb20vMjAyNi8wMS8xNS91cy10YWl3YW4tY2hpcHMtZGVhbC1jaGluYS5odG1sIn0&amp;amp;signature=AQAAAd7FOIvL4CDI6TVilQ7BsdgzopzjJrgQdEzfltn5cRPG&amp;amp;gcReferrer=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cnbc.com%2F2026%2F01%2F15%2Fus-taiwan-chips-deal-china.html" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company (TSNC) is already in position to take advantage of the new trade agreement with further expansion in Arizona. The major Taiwanese chip manufacturer had previously committed to investing &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/tsmc-is-investing-an-additional-100-billion-into-semiconductor-manufacturing-in-the-us-130045776.html" target="_blank"&gt;$100 billion&lt;/a&gt; in its US operations over four years. Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick told &lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt; in an interview that the current US government wants to bring 40 percent of Taiwan's semiconductor supply chain stateside, continuing to use tariffs as an incentive. &amp;quot;If they don’t build in America, the tariff’s likely to be 100 percent,” Lutnick said.&lt;/p&gt;This article originally appeared on Engadget at https://www.engadget.com/computing/a-250-billion-trade-deal-will-see-taiwan-bring-more-semiconductor-production-to-the-us-224326501.html?src=rss&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Engadget | Score: 60&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 22:43:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Feds Drop $11 Million to Bring High-Speed Internet to Rural Saskatchewan</title><link>https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/2026/01/17/feds-drop-11-million-to-bring-high-speed-internet-to-rural-saskatchewan/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=feds-drop-11-million-to-bring-high-speed-internet-to-rural-saskatchewan</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The federal government said on Friday is putting up more than $11 million to help fix spotty internet in rural and remote parts of Saskatchewan. The new funding will cover four major projects aimed at connecting over 1,920 homes (about $5,729/home) across 28 different communities, including nearly 200 Indigenous households. Announced in Meadow Lake by [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/2026/01/17/feds-drop-11-million-to-bring-high-speed-internet-to-rural-saskatchewan/"&gt;Feds Drop $11 Million to Bring High-Speed Internet to Rural Saskatchewan&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.iphoneincanada.ca"&gt;iPhone in Canada&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: iPhone in Canada Blog - Tips, Tricks, News, and Tutorials for Canadian iPhone Users | Score: 65&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:00:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vanderhoof to weather $580K revenue loss with little change to taxes</title><link>https://wltribune.com/2026/01/16/vanderhoof-to-weather-580k-revenue-loss-with-little-change-to-taxes/</link><description>Vanderhoof to weather $580K revenue loss with little change to taxes&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Williams Lake Tribune | Score: 65&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>9 Best Wi-Fi Routers of 2026 for Working, Gaming, and Streaming</title><link>https://www.wired.com/gallery/best-wifi-routers/</link><description>Don’t suffer the buffer. These WIRED-tested home routers will deliver reliable internet across your home, whatever your needs or budget.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: WIRED | Score: 65&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>7 reasons you should stop buying Wi-Fi smart bulbs</title><link>https://www.makeuseof.com/reasons-stop-buying-wi-fi-smart-bulbs/</link><description>Wi-Fi smart bulbs are the weakest link in your smart home.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: MakeUseOf.com | Score: 65&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 17:30:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Visualizations of the growing undersea network of submarine cables, 2013-2025....</title><link>https://kottke.org/26/01/0048170-visualizations-of-the-gro</link><description>&lt;a href="https://blog.telegeography.com/submarine-cables-over-time-through-the-years"&gt;Visualizations of the growing undersea network of submarine cables, 2013-2025&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Kottke.org | Score: 65&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 19:53:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Photos of China&amp;#8217;s Green Energy Transition</title><link>https://kottke.org/26/01/photos-of-chinas-green-energy-transition</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" height="2997" src="https://kottke.org/cdn-cgi/image/format=auto,fit=scale-down,width=1200,metadata=none/images/posts/01/img-48188-01.jpg" width="4000" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" height="1874" src="https://kottke.org/cdn-cgi/image/format=auto,fit=scale-down,width=1200,metadata=none/images/posts/01/img-48188-02.jpg" width="2500" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" height="960" src="https://kottke.org/cdn-cgi/image/format=auto,fit=scale-down,width=1200,metadata=none/images/posts/01/img-48188-03.jpg" width="1440" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" height="1500" src="https://kottke.org/cdn-cgi/image/format=auto,fit=scale-down,width=1200,metadata=none/images/posts/01/img-48188-04.jpg" width="2000" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" height="1500" src="https://kottke.org/cdn-cgi/image/format=auto,fit=scale-down,width=1200,metadata=none/images/posts/01/img-48188-05.jpg" width="2000" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" height="1333" src="https://kottke.org/cdn-cgi/image/format=auto,fit=scale-down,width=1200,metadata=none/images/posts/01/img-48188-06.jpg" width="2000" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://e360.yale.edu/digest/china-renewable-photo-essay"&gt;These&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.greenpeace.org/international/story/79654/powering-change-a-visual-journey-into-chinas-green-transition/"&gt;photos&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/thomaschuphoto/"&gt;Chu Weimin&lt;/a&gt; show the mind-boggling scale of China&amp;#8217;s green energy buildout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year China installed more than half of all wind and solar added globally. In May alone, it added enough renewable energy to power Poland, installing solar panels at a rate of roughly 100 every second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The massive buildout is happening across the country, from crowded eastern cities increasingly topped by rooftop solar panels to remote western deserts where colossal wind farms sprawl across the landscape.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

        

         &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tags:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://kottke.org/tag/China"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href="https://kottke.org/tag/Chu%20Weimin"&gt;Chu Weimin&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href="https://kottke.org/tag/energy"&gt;energy&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href="https://kottke.org/tag/photography"&gt;photography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Kottke.org | Score: 65&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:08:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICE let an AI decide who gets a badge, and the AI said "sure, why not"</title><link>https://boingboing.net/2026/01/16/ice-let-an-ai-decide-who-gets-a-badge-and-the-ai-said-sure-why-not.html</link><description>&lt;a href="https://boingboing.net/2026/01/16/ice-let-an-ai-decide-who-gets-a-badge-and-the-ai-said-sure-why-not.html" rel="nofollow" title="ICE let an AI decide who gets a badge, and the AI said &amp;quot;sure, why not&amp;quot;"&gt;&lt;img alt="&amp;quot;NO ICE&amp;quot; sticker spotted in Tempe, AZ. photo: Jennifer Sandlin" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1056" src="https://i0.wp.com/boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/22NO-ICE22-sticker-spotted-in-Tempe2C-AZ.-photo-Je.jpg?fit=1080%2C1056&amp;amp;quality=60&amp;amp;ssl=1" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 5px;" width="1080" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Congratulations, an LLM liked your resume! Here is your gun and your badge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICE asked a large language model to review applicants' resumes. Sadly, the LLM didn't understand the difference between mall cops and actual law enforcement. It seems the AI fast-tracked anyone who used the word "officer" in any context. &amp;#8212; &lt;a class="read-more" href="https://boingboing.net/2026/01/16/ice-let-an-ai-decide-who-gets-a-badge-and-the-ai-said-sure-why-not.html"&gt;Read the rest &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://boingboing.net/2026/01/16/ice-let-an-ai-decide-who-gets-a-badge-and-the-ai-said-sure-why-not.html"&gt;ICE let an AI decide who gets a badge, and the AI said &amp;quot;sure, why not&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://boingboing.net"&gt;Boing Boing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Boing Boing | Score: 65&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:15:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>OpenAI to test ads in ChatGPT as it burns through billions</title><link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2026/01/openai-to-test-ads-in-chatgpt-as-it-burns-through-billions/</link><description>Ads coming to free tier and new $8/month ChatGPT Go plan in US.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Ars Technica – Technology Lab | Score: 65&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 21:20:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Affordability, respite shortfall, making life difficult for B.C. seniors: advocate</title><link>https://wltribune.com/2026/01/17/affordability-respite-shortfall-making-life-difficult-for-b-c-seniors-advocate/</link><description>Affordability, respite shortfall, making life difficult for B.C. seniors: advocate&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Williams Lake Tribune | Score: 70&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>State and Federal Lawmakers Want Data Centers to Pay More for Energy</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/15/business/energy-environment/data-center-energy-electricity-costs.html</link><description>Despite many proposals, there is little consensus among governors, lawmakers and tech executives about exactly how much the companies behind data centers should pay for electricity.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: NYT &gt; Business | Score: 70&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 01:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>I replaced this professional Microsoft tool with open-source software and should've done it sooner</title><link>https://www.makeuseof.com/replaced-professional-microsoft-tool-with-open-source-software/</link><description>Making documentation simpler, faster, and truly team-friendly.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: MakeUseOf.com | Score: 70&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 15:00:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ASUS has stopped producing the NVIDIA RTX 5070 Ti and 5060 Ti 16GB, saying they've reached 'end of life'</title><link>https://www.engadget.com/gaming/pc/asus-has-stopped-producing-the-nvidia-rtx-5070-ti-and-5060-ti-16gb-saying-theyve-reached-end-of-life-162012253.html?src=rss</link><description>&lt;p&gt;YouTube channel &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/@Hardwareunboxed" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hardware Unboxed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is reporting that ASUS has stopped producing the &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.engadget.com/gaming/pc/nvidia-geforce-5070-ti-review-a-sensible-4k-powerhouse-for-749-140023082.html" target="_blank"&gt;RTX 5070 Ti&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.engadget.com/gaming/pc/nvidia-rtx-5060-ti-16gb-review-a-solid-semi-budget-gpu-for-429-but-good-luck-scoring-that-price-130058124.html" target="_blank"&gt;5060 Ti 16GB&lt;/a&gt; due to the ongoing memory crunch. In its &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yteN21aJEvE" target="_blank"&gt;most recent video&lt;/a&gt;, the channel states ASUS “explicitly” told it the RTX 5070 Ti is “currently facing a supply shortage.” As a result, the company has “placed the model into end of life status,” and no longer plans to produce it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="width: 100%; height: 0; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hardware Unboxed &lt;/em&gt;also spoke to retailers in Australia, who told the channel the 5070 Ti is “no longer available to purchase from partners and distributors,” adding they expect that to be the case throughout at least the first quarter of the year.  The 5060 Ti 16GB “is almost done as well,&amp;quot; with ASUS stating  it no longer plans to produce that model going forward either. Both GPUs are 16GB models, making them more expensive to manufacture in the current economic climate.  And while there might be some hope of the 5070 Ti and 5060 Ti 16GB returning later this year, the channel suggests both are unlikely to make a comeback. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Demand for GeForce RTX GPUs is strong, and memory supply is constrained. We continue to ship all GeForce SKUs and are working closely with our suppliers to maximize memory availability,” a NVIDIA spokesperson told Engadget. ASUS did not immediately respond to Engadget’s comment request.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After uploading its video, &lt;em&gt;Hardware Unboxed &lt;/em&gt;published a clarification. “ASUS did not tell us that NVIDIA said the RTX 5070 Ti has been discontinued. ASUS told us there is very little supply of the 5070 Ti, so their own 5070 Ti products (e.g, the Prime and TUF Gaming) have been put into end of life status,” the &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/@Hardwareunboxed/posts" target="_blank"&gt;channel said&lt;/a&gt;. “With retailers also unable to source 5070 Ti SKUs from any AIB, this effectively makes it a dead product.”  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The AI boom has created an insatiable demand for RAM and other computer components from data center infrastructure companies. In response, many memory manufacturers have shifted their production lines to focus on high bandwidth memory for those clients at the expense of their regular offerings, leading to dramatically increased prices among consumer &lt;a class="link" href="https://investors.micron.com/news-releases/news-release-details/micron-announces-exit-crucial-consumer-business" target="_blank"&gt;RAM kits&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.engadget.com/gaming/pc/the-ai-boom-could-soon-send-gpu-prices-soaring-so-nows-a-good-time-to-buy-one-153000063.html" target="_blank"&gt;GPUs&lt;/a&gt; and SSDs. In December, Micron Technology announced it would &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.engadget.com/computing/crucial-is-a-casualty-of-ais-hunger-for-ram-185910113.html" target="_blank"&gt;wind down its consumer-facing Crucial brand&lt;/a&gt; to focus exclusively on providing components to the AI industry.    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ASUS is the first of NVIDIA’s add-in board (AIB) partners to comment on the memory crunch. AIBs are the companies that produce the majority of GPUs you can buy from NVIDIA and AMD.   Historically, NVIDIA has provided its board partners with both the die and memory needed to make a graphics cards. However, a &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.tomshardware.com/pc-components/gpus/nvidia-reportedly-no-longer-supplying-vram-to-its-gpu-board-partners-in-response-to-memory-crunch-rumor-claims-vendors-will-only-get-the-die-forced-to-source-memory-on-their-own" target="_blank"&gt;recent rumor&lt;/a&gt; suggested the company had told it partners they would need to start sourcing memory on their own.   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 12:55PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;Added more context.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 2:06PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;: Added comment from NVIDIA. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 6:31PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;: Added additional comment from &lt;em&gt;Hardware Unboxed&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;This article originally appeared on Engadget at https://www.engadget.com/gaming/pc/asus-has-stopped-producing-the-nvidia-rtx-5070-ti-and-5060-ti-16gb-saying-theyve-reached-end-of-life-162012253.html?src=rss&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Engadget | Score: 70&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 23:32:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mandiant releases rainbow table that cracks weak admin password in 12 hours</title><link>https://arstechnica.com/security/2026/01/mandiant-releases-rainbow-table-that-cracks-weak-admin-password-in-12-hours/</link><description>Windows laggards still using the vulnerable hashing function: Your days are numbered.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Ars Technica – Technology Lab | Score: 70&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 21:05:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Experts point to climate change as root cause of Victoria’s January blossoms</title><link>https://wltribune.com/2026/01/16/experts-point-to-climate-change-as-root-cause-of-victorias-january-blossoms/</link><description>Experts point to climate change as root cause of Victoria’s January blossoms&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Williams Lake Tribune | Score: 75&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>7 Best Mesh Wi-Fi Systems (2026), Tested in a Tech Reviewer's Home</title><link>https://www.wired.com/story/best-mesh-wifi-routers/</link><description>Forget about patchy internet connections and dead spots in the house. These WIRED-tested multiroom mesh systems will get you online in no time.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: WIRED | Score: 75&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why There’s No Single Best Way To Store Information</title><link>https://www.quantamagazine.org/why-theres-no-single-best-way-to-store-information-20260116/</link><description>The math of data structures helps us understand how different storage systems come with different trade-offs between resources such as time and memory.            &lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/why-theres-no-single-best-way-to-store-information-20260116/" target="_blank"&gt;Why There’s No Single Best Way To Store Information&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org" target="_blank"&gt;Quanta Magazine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Quanta Magazine | Score: 75&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:10:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Wall Street Turned Its Back on Climate Change</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/17/climate/how-wall-street-turned-its-back-on-climate-change.html</link><description>Six years after the financial industry pledged to use trillions to fight climate change and reshape finance, its efforts have largely collapsed.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: NYT &gt; Top Stories | Score: 75&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 13:14:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Activists in Iran Are Using Starlink to Stay Online</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/15/technology/iran-online-starlink.html</link><description>Activists spent years preparing for a communications blackout in Iran, smuggling in Starlink satellite internet systems and making digital shutdowns harder for the authorities to enforce.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: NYT &gt; Business | Score: 75&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:24:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Download: cut through AI coding hype, and biotech trends to watch</title><link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2026/01/16/1131375/the-download-ai-coding-hype-and-biotech-trends-to-watch/</link><description>This is today&amp;#8217;s edition of&amp;#160;The Download,&amp;#160;our weekday newsletter that provides a daily dose of what&amp;#8217;s going on in the world of technology. AI coding is now everywhere. But not everyone is convinced.   Depending who you ask, AI-powered coding is either giving software developers an unprecedented productivity boost or churning out masses of poorly designed code&amp;#8230;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: MIT Technology Review | Score: 75&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:59:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>By All Measures. &amp;#8220;Our scales are too imbalanced; we are unable to...</title><link>https://kottke.org/26/01/0048178-by-all-measures-our-scale</link><description>&lt;a href="https://longreads.com/2026/01/13/scale-climate-doomsday-clock/"&gt;By All Measures&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;#8220;Our scales are too imbalanced; we are unable to think the unthinkable. It goes without saying that it can be paralyzing, demoralizing, to be an individual acting as part of the collective, globe-sized world.&amp;#8221;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Kottke.org | Score: 75&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 21:22:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Morning After: ASUS stops making some NVIDIA GPUs due to memory supply crunch</title><link>https://www.engadget.com/general/the-morning-after-engadget-newsletter-121506027.html?src=rss</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If you thought we were &lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/computing/ces-2026-proved-the-pc-industry-is-hosed-this-year-174500314.html"&gt;&lt;ins&gt;exaggerating&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the hunger for memory and GPUs is making many companies reassess their priorities. YouTube channel Hardware Unboxed discovered ASUS has stopped producing the RTX 5070 Ti and 5060 Ti 16GB due to the ongoing memory crunch. Both GPUs are 16GB models, making them more expensive to manufacture in the current climate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Demand for GeForce RTX GPUs is strong, and memory supply is constrained. We continue to ship all GeForce SKUs and are working closely with our suppliers to maximize memory availability,” an NVIDIA spokesperson told Engadget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At CES 2026, we saw PCs and computing in the next 12 months will have higher prices and more limited availability for consumers. At the end of 2025, RAM prices skyrocketed, driven by demand from AI data centers. That’s not stopping anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Mat Smith&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="jump-link-the-other-big-stories-and-deals-this-morning"&gt;The other big stories (and deals) this morning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/gaming/nintendo/the-animal-crossing-new-horizons-30-expansion-has-arrived-earlier-than-expected-160739394.html"&gt;&lt;ins&gt;The Animal Crossing: New Horizons 3.0 expansion has arrived earlier than expected&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/mobile/how-to-claim-verizons-20-credit-for-wednesdays-service-outage-171909695.html"&gt;&lt;ins&gt;How to claim Verizon’s $20 credit for Wednesday’s service outage&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/deals/get-one-month-of-the-disney-and-hulu-bundle-for-only-10-192814218.html"&gt;&lt;ins&gt;Get one month of the Disney+ and Hulu bundle for only $10&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/home/home-theater/valerion-visionmaster-max-projector-review-near-perfect-image-quality-comes-at-a-price-140045939.html"&gt;&lt;ins&gt;Valerion VisionMaster Max projector review: Near-perfect image quality comes at a price&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id="jump-link-matthew-mcconaughey-just-trademarked-himself"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/ai/matthew-mcconaughey-fights-unauthorized-ai-likenesses-by-trademarking-himself-130000567.html"&gt;Matthew McConaughey just trademarked himself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="jump-link-in-the-fight-against-ai"&gt;In the fight against AI.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="TMA" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2026-01/e93f6ce1-f2d1-11f0-bd5f-40209b88cdb9" style="height: 427px; width: 640px;" /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;div class="photo-credit"&gt;Getty&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew McConaughey filed trademark applications to prevent AI companies from using his likeness without permission, and the US Patent and Trademark Office has approved eight so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trademarks were for video and audio clips featuring the actor staring, smiling and talking. One was for an audio recording of him saying “alright, alright, alright,” his catchphrase from the movie&lt;em&gt; Dazed and Confused. &lt;/em&gt;Under the law, it’s already prohibited for companies to steal someone’s likeness to sell products. However, given the vague rules governing the use of someone’s likeness, McConaughey is taking a proactive approach. McConaughey himself is an investor in ElevenLabs and has partnered with the AI startup to create a Spanish version of his newsletter. Está bien, está bien, está bien.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/ai/matthew-mcconaughey-fights-unauthorized-ai-likenesses-by-trademarking-himself-130000567.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continue reading.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id="jump-link-amazon-is-making-a-fallout-competition-reality-tv-show"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/entertainment/tv-movies/amazon-is-making-a-fallout-shelter-competition-reality-tv-show-190151855.html"&gt;Amazon is making a Fallout competition reality TV show&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="jump-link-addiction-radiation-poisoning-skeletal-law-enforcement"&gt;Addiction! Radiation poisoning! Skeletal law enforcement?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/entertainment/tv-movies/amazon-is-making-a-fallout-shelter-competition-reality-tv-show-190151855.html"&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="TMA" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2026-01/e93f6ce0-f2d1-11f0-bfff-914184a87fc4" style="height: 360px; width: 640px;" /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;div class="photo-credit"&gt;AMAZON&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second season of Amazon’s excellent Fallout show is currently streaming, but the company is already looking to generate more revenue from its license to the well-regarded game series. Prime Video has greenlit an unscripted reality show titled &lt;em&gt;Fallout Shelter&lt;/em&gt;. It will be a 10-episode run with Studio Lambert, the team behind reality projects including &lt;em&gt;Squid Game: The Challenge &lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt; The Traitors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/entertainment/tv-movies/amazon-is-making-a-fallout-shelter-competition-reality-tv-show-190151855.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continue reading.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;span id="end-legacy-contents"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h2 id="jump-link-x-says-grok-will-no-longer-edit-images-of-real-people-into-bikinis"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/ai/x-says-grok-will-no-longer-edit-images-of-real-people-into-bikinis-231430257.html"&gt;X says Grok will no longer edit images of real people into bikinis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="jump-link-but-image-generation-isnt-going-anywhere"&gt;But image generation isn’t going anywhere.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id="jump-link-"&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following numerous complaints and several state and national investigations, X is revising its policies on Grok’s image-editing capabilities. New safeguards will place Grok’s image-generating features behind X’s subscription offering, and it will geoblock all users’ ability to generate images of real people in… well, less clothing, in regions where it’s illegal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;California Attorney General Rob Bonta cited one analysis that found “more than half of the 20,000 images generated by xAI between Christmas and New Year depicted people in minimal clothing.” That’s been the primary use?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/ai/x-says-grok-will-no-longer-edit-images-of-real-people-into-bikinis-231430257.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continue reading.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;This article originally appeared on Engadget at https://www.engadget.com/general/the-morning-after-engadget-newsletter-121506027.html?src=rss&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Engadget | Score: 75&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:15:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rackspace customers grapple with “devastating” email hosting price hike</title><link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2026/01/rackspace-raises-email-hosting-prices-by-as-much-as-706-percent/</link><description>Reseller says Rackspace plans to charge it 706 percent more.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Ars Technica – Technology Lab | Score: 75&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 23:15:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The shape of time</title><link>https://aeon.co/essays/when-we-turned-time-into-a-line-we-reimagined-past-and-future?utm_source=rss-feed</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://images.aeonmedia.co/images/2c9bedad-106d-4d05-b35f-f5d6b4760880/v2-adams_synchronological_chart_1881.jpg?width=1200&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;format=auto" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the 19th century, the linear idea of time became dominant – with profound implications for how we experience the world&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;- by Emily Thomas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aeon.co/essays/when-we-turned-time-into-a-line-we-reimagined-past-and-future?utm_source=rss-feed"&gt;Read on Aeon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Aeon Essays | Score: 75&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TSMC says AI demand is “endless” after record Q4 earnings</title><link>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2026/01/tsmc-says-ai-demand-is-endless-after-record-q4-earnings/</link><description>Amid fears of bubble, world's top chipmaker TSMC says customers just keep asking for more.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Ars Technica – Technology Lab | Score: 85&lt;/em&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:55:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>